

A.K. Pratap Aditya

https://pratapaditya.github.io

🩎 New Delhi, India

Senior User Experience (UX) Engineer № Prataparya2012@gmail.com

\(\) +91- 9868375908

"Imbuing empathy and perspective through 12+ years' experience in UX design and UI development."

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY -

Experienced Senior User experience (UX) engineer skilled in crossproject design and team leadership. Proven success in building and deploying design systems, applying best practices in client-side technology, cross-platform solutions with hybrid apps. Enthusiastic about using data, technology, and creativity to tackle intricate challenges, driving growth with modern tools and cohesive teamwork.

EXPERIENCE -

Cheers Interactive (p) Limited, A market research MNC company

UX Analyst: (May 2023 to present)

- Led UX design team to implement a collaborative design process and UI guidelines for consistent high-end designs that align with client requirements.
- Reduced Project delivery timeline by 25% through team leadership

Secure meters Limited, A Utility based CMMI 3 MNC company

Senior UX Engineer (April 2020 to May 2023)

- Coordinated a discovery session that resulted in enhanced communication among designers and developers, ensuring alignment with business goals at a 100% success rate.
- 100% Identified and fixed issue reported in existing code and solution- exploration for interactive plugins for team.
- Contributed to a 15% increase in user engagement through strategic product enhancement

SKILLS -

Programming

HTML5 CSS3 Angular 8 Bootstrap4 jQuery 3.0 Java script ES5/6 ★ ★ ★ ☆ ☆ SCSS Cordova 5.0 PHP 6.0

Tool

Photoshop CS6 Adobe XD 56.0 Just in mind 8.0 VS code 1.8

User experience design skill

User research | Persona Wire-frame | Lo-fi/Hi-fi proto User journey | Empathy map | Strategic planning

User Interface design skill

- Responsive web / mobile
- Multimedia Audio/video
- Graphics / Animation
- Art & hand drawing

UX developer (April 2016- March 2020)

- Enhanced overall user engagement by 30% with UX analysis and intuitive UI.
- Improved team productivity by 15% through effective collaboration
- Bug free development of UI pages, widgets using HTML, CSS3, Bootstrap, JS, jQuery, Ajax & Angular as per the project architecture and mockups.

Web designer (March 2011-March 2016)

- Creative cross PSD mockup and 100% responsive and tableless conversion.
- Excelled template design/ development and utility training of widgets to developers.

Strength

- Data driven decision
 Leveraging analytics to inform product
- Cross function Leadership
 Experience leading diverse, high performing design and development team

ACHIEVEMENTS —

- Top Learner Secure -award
- Client handling employee award
- Development of drag and drop SCADA system.
- UX team / design system implementation award

National score exam ranking

GATE (CS-IT M. Tech)/2010/92.79 Percentile GATE (CS-IT M. Tech) 2009/87.28 Percentile JNU Entrance (CS-M Tech)/2008/50 AIR

PERSONAL DOSSIER —

Nationality: Indian

Hindi: Native English: Fluent

EDUCATION —

MCA (Master of Computer Application)
NISCAIR, IGNOU, Delhi / 1st class

COP-U (Language proficiency)

COF-0 (Language proficier

JNU, New Delhi / 1st class

BIT (Bachelor of Information Tech)

IGNOU, New Delhi / 1st class

BTEC-HND (Computing & multimedia)

Edexcel (UK, London) / 1st class

ACCOMPLISHMENT ——

Web application projects AS UX designer

- ABT (Availability Based Tariff)
- MDAS (Meter Data Acquisition System)
- RAPDRP Gas-MBC SAMAST DSM

Progressive web app projects **AS** Theme designer and developer **with** angular 6, Dojo, jsPlumb, D3

- GIS (Geographical information System)
- NGDCS-New Generation Smart Home
- MIMIC-Canvas (Drag-Drop SCADA system)

Worked on Hybrid android app **AS** Full stack developer **with** Cordova, php, BS4, jQuery

- smart panchayat ■
- Stand-N-stride
- Pratapaditya Shubhashray Desi Sawari

CERTIFICATION —





Mobile Experience: 2021

Usability Testing: 2021

Microsoft



Adv. professional: 2021

Design thinking: 2021

BLOG AND LINK -

https://pratapaditya.github.io

https://freeux24.wordpress.com/

https://www.linkedin.com/in/pratap-aditya/